{"tossups": [{"question": "One character in this play delivers a monologue criticizing men whose \u201cwagging tongues\u2026 dishonor the shrine before which they lie.\u201d A servant in this play describes the title character eating mutton in front of a sick woman with no appetite. That title character claims \u201cseeing your bosom causes me grief\u201d while telling another to cover herself with a handkerchief. An eviction notice helping the villain of this play is delivered by (*) Monsieur Loyal, who is mocked by the servant Dorine. At Elmire\u2019s behest, her husband hides under a table to discover the sexual advances of this play\u2019s title character; he is eventually arrested by forces under Louis XIV, saving Orgon\u2019s family. For 10 points, name this Moliere play centering on the title hypocrite.", "answer": "Tartuffe", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tartuffe</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Tartuffe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a flashback of a story set in this conflict, the narrator\u2019s father takes him to get ice cream after his girlfriend Linda \u201ckicked the bucket\u201d from a brain tumor. After being saved from an attack, a character who serves in this war claims \u201cthe magic has not been lost.\u201d One character faints before traveling to the title \u201cDentist\u201d during this war, and eventually finds out that his toothache was from a \u201cperfectly good tooth.\u201d A necklace of tongues is worn by Mary Anne during this conflict, the focus of a book in which (*) Elroy Berghdahl takes the narrator fishing \u201cOn the Rainy River.\u201d In a book set during this conflict, Kiowa dies along the banks of the Song Tra Bong, while Jimmy Cross and his fellow soldier bring the title objects. For 10 points, name this war, the setting of Tim O\u2019Brien\u2019s The Things They Carried.", "answer": "Vietnam War", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Vietnam War</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Vietnam War"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one story by this author, Grant reluctantly has an affair with Marian to allow Aubrey to stay with Fiona, his Alzheimer\u2019s ridden wife. In addition to \u201cThe Bear Came Over the Mountain,\u201d this author wrote a story in which the protagonist stays with her daughter Judith and misses her other daughter Nichola. In one story by this author, a student from the Greenhill School plays a rendition of Gluck\u2019s (*) Orfeo ed Eurydice. A girl with Down Syndrome plays the title song at a piano recital hosted by Miss Marsalles in that story by this author. Janet visits a planetarium and goes to the Toronto hospital to quiz her father on Ganymede, one of the title objects in another story by this author. For 10 points, name this author of \u201cDance of the Happy Shades\u201d and \u201cThe Moons of Jupiter,\u201d the Canadian winner of the 2013 Nobel Prize in Literature.", "answer": "Alice Munro", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Alice <b><u>Munro</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alice Munro"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poet from this country described the title objects standing \u201cat night, in light of the soul\u201d after declaring \u201cI dream of cloisters of marble\u201d in one poem. The protagonist of a novel from this country turns into a goose but is rejected by the goose clan. That protagonist earlier raped Mademoiselle Floridor. A poet from this country wrote about preparing the title object \u201cfor the sincere friend\u201d and \u201cfor the (*) cruel person\u201d in a poem whose speaker prepares \u201cneither nettles nor thorns.\u201d The Lord of Poison, Macandal, kills cattle in The Kingdom of this World, a novel written from this country. A poet from this country wrote about cultivating a white rose in a poem published in his collection Versos Sencillos, from which the patriotic song \u201cGuantanamera\u201d was adapted. Alejo Carpentier and Jose Marti were from, for 10 points, what country whose capital is Havana?", "answer": "Republic of Cuba", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>Cuba</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Republic of Cuba"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a play by this author, Mr. Frick and Mr. Hamilton meet in a mental hospital where their wives are recovering and argue about the values of America. That play is The Last Yankee. This author adapted Ibsen\u2019s An Enemy of the People to remove its positive outlook on eugenics and racial determinism. In another play by this writer, a man becomes angered at an Italian immigrant who is a beautiful singer and is in love with his niece. In another of this man\u2019s plays, a man kills himself after his son discovers he sold faulty (*) airplane parts that killed his brother Larry during World War I. This man also wrote a play in which a rubber hose is found in a basement by Linda, whose husband later kills himself in a car crash. For 10 points, name this author of A View From the Bridge, All My Sons, and Death of a Salesman.", "answer": "Arthur Miller", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Arthur <b><u>Miller</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Arthur Miller"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This novel\u2019s protagonist attempts to break into a certain building to demonstrate that it can be entered without a key. While arriving at this novel\u2019s central location, characters are surprised to see a cellarer complaining about the unexpected disappearance of a horse. After having sex with a village girl in the kitchen, this novel\u2019s narrator discovers that the \u201cFinis Africae\u201d is actually a secret room. One character is found dead in a vat of pig\u2019s blood in this novel, in which the inquisitor (*) Bernard Gui fails to execute a hunchbacked man. The blind Jorge of Burgos poisons a recurring object in this novel, a sequel to Aristotle's Poetics, to cover up his murders. Adso of Melk and William of Baskerville appear in, for 10 points, what novel by Umberto Eco?", "answer": "The Name of The Rose [or Il nome della rosa]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Name of The Rose</u></b> [or <b><u>Il nome della rosa</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Name of The Rose", "Il nome della rosa"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One poem by this author says, \u201clet geese / Gabble and hiss, but heroes seek release\u201d before noting that the title figure sees \u201clight anatomized.\u201d In another poem by this author, a character says to her son \u201ccome, climb onto my lap, / And I\u2019ll chafe your little bones.\u201d In that poem, the narrator was so poor that they \u201cburned up the chairs / And sat on the floor.\u201d The narrator of another poem by this author says that an object \u201cgives a lovely light.\u201d In addition to (*) \u201cEuclid alone has looked on beauty bare,\u201d this author wrote a poem in which a character creates \u201cthe clothes of a king\u2019s son / Just my size.\u201d This author of \u201cThe Ballad of the Harp-Weaver\" also wrote a work that states \u201cmy candle burns at both ends.\u201d For 10 points, name this poet who wrote the collection A Few Figs from Thistles.", "answer": "Edna St. Vincent Millay", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Edna St. Vincent <b><u>Millay</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Edna St. Vincent Millay"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Rumanian magician Rostipov is called in to examine a character in this novel. Another character in it kicks Ferula out of his house after he finds her in bed with his wife. A prostitute in this novel saves the protagonist\u2019s granddaughter years after meeting the protagonist at the Red Lantern brothel. Pornographic pictures of Indian servants lead a character in this novel to leave Jean de (*) Satigny. This novel begins with the sentence \u201cBarabbas came to us by sea.\u201d Blanca\u2019s father knocks out her mother\u2019s teeth and cuts off three of Pedro Tercero\u2019s fingers in this novel. Rosa the Beautiful gets poisoned in place of her father in this novel, leading her clairvoyant sister Clara to take a vow of silence until she meets Esteban, whom she then marries. For 10 points, name this novel about the del Valle and Trueba families by Isabel Allende.", "answer": "The House of the Spirits [or La casa de los espiritus]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The House of the Spirits</u></b> [or <b><u>La casa de los espiritus</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The House of the Spirits", "La casa de los espiritus"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Two people with this profession are described as \u201ca hoodoo\u201d and \u201ca cake\u201d in one poem. After a group yells \u201cKill him!\u201d at one person in that poem, a character with this profession gives \u201ca smile of Christian charity.\u201d In a novel, Max Mercy offers one character with this profession $5,000 and introduces him to Gus Sands, while another character with this profession dies after running into a wall. That character is Bump (*) Bailey. A poem that claims \u201cthe outlook wasn\u2019t brilliant for\u201d a group of these people later laments that \u201cthere is no joy in Mudville.\u201d Harriet Bird shoots one person with this profession, who uses Wonderboy and is named Roy Hobbs. The most famous poem by Ernest Thayer and novel by Bernard Malamud both center on characters with this profession. For 10 points, name this profession of the protagonists of The Natural and \u201cCasey at the Bat.\u201d", "answer": "baseball players [or equivalents; accept specific positions like pitcher, catcher, etc.; prompt on \u201cathlete,\u201d \u201cballplayer,\u201d or anything describing a person who plays sports]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>baseball players</u></b> [ or equivalents; accept <b><u>specific positions like pitcher, catcher, etc.</u></b>; prompt on <u>\u201cathlete,\u201d \u201cballplayer,\u201d</u> or <u>anything describing a person who plays sports</u>]", "acceptable": ["baseball players", "specific positions like pitcher, catcher, etc."], "promptable": ["\u201cathlete,\u201d \u201cballplayer,\u201d", "anything describing a person who plays sports"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of one poem in this collection is hated by his mother but realizes that his suffering is the path towards a \u201cdiadem of dazzling splendor\u201d and the \u201ccrown\u2026 made of nothing but pure light.\u201d One poem in this collection talks about perfumes that are \u201cas cool as the flesh of children\u201d and \u201csweet as oboes.\u201d That poem in this collection declares that \u201cNature is a temple\u201d and is titled (*) \u201cCorrespondences.\u201d A character in one poem in this collection \u201cdreams of scaffolds as he smokes his hookah pipe.\u201d Another poem in this collection opens \u201cAndromache, I think of you!\u201d One poem in this collection invokes the idea of \u201cennui\u201d before addressing a \u201chypocrite reader.\u201d This collection includes the sections \u201cWine,\u201d \u201cRevolt,\u201d and \u201cSpleen and Ideal.\u201d For 10 points, name this poetry collection by Charles Baudelaire.", "answer": "Les Fleurs du Mal [or The Flowers of Evil]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Les Fleurs du Mal</u></b> [or <b><u>The Flowers of Evil</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Les Fleurs du Mal", "The Flowers of Evil"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "After his colleague is unsatisfied, this man\u2019s boss sees a character \u201cglowing like a brass boiler\u201d and comments on his hands among \u201cblotted\u201d objects. The story this man appears in describes its central setting as \u201cdeserted as Petra\u201d before comparing this man to \u201cMarius brooding among the ruins of Carthage.\u201d This person fixes his eyes on a bust of Cicero behind one character, who is dissuaded from going to Trinity Church because of this man\u2019s appearance. At the end of the story this character appears in, the narrator pays a (*) grub-man to feed him while he\u2019s imprisoned in the Tombs. At the beginning of that work set mostly in a Wall Street office, the narrator introduces coworkers of this man such as Turkey, Ginger Nut, and Nippers. For 10 points, name this title scrivener of a Herman Melville story who famously exclaims \u201cI would prefer not to.\u201d", "answer": "Bartleby the Scrivener", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bartleby the Scrivener</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bartleby the Scrivener"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A sonnet titled for this person describes \u201cpassions\u2026 stamped on these lifeless things,\u201d while a \u201cLeg remaining to disclose\u201d is mentioned in another poem about him. That poem describes a \u201csite\u201d of a \u201cforgotten\u201d city. Another poem about this person, which was written under the pseudonym Glirastes, mentions a (*) \u201chand that mocked them\u201d and a \u201cheart that fed.\u201d Two poems about this person were published in The Examiner, one of which was written by Horace Smith. \u201c[T]runkless legs of stone\u201d and a \u201csneer of cold command\u201d are described in a poem about this man that tells the readers to \u201clook on [this man\u2019s] works, and despair!\u201d For 10 points, name this Egyptian pharaoh called the \u201cKing of Kings,\u201d the subject of a Percy Bysshe Shelley poem.", "answer": "Ozymandias [or Ramesses II; or Ramesses the Great; prompt on Ramesses]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ozymandias</u></b> [or <b><u>Ramesses II</u></b>; or <b><u>Ramesses the Great</u></b>; prompt on <u>Ramesses</u>]", "acceptable": ["Ozymandias", "Ramesses II", "Ramesses the Great"], "promptable": ["Ramesses"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one of this author\u2019s novels, the chef Dick Halloran gets a distress call from another character, causing him to rush to Colorado, where he is attacked by topiaries. In another work by this author, a young girl is unaware that she is having her period after her mother refuses to inform her about them, causing classmates to throw tampons at her in gym class. A character in that novel, Sue Snell, convinces the title character she had no role in a prank, and eventually writes a memoir about her senior (*) prom. In another novel by this author, \u201cThe Losers Club\u201d fend off the bully Bowers before meeting the title character, a shapeshifting being who awakens once every 27 years. That creature terrorizes the children of Derry, Maine, most notably in the form of Pennywise the Dancing Clown. For 10 points, name this American horror writer of The Shining, Carrie and It.", "answer": "Stephen King", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Stephen <b><u>King</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Stephen King"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this play says he will \"sell all [his] land\" to pay another character instead of committing suicide out of shame. Another character is described as \"an honest man\" before he is instructed to give his \"worst of thoughts / The worst of words.\" One character in this play who is called a \u201cmurderous coxcomb\u201d by his wife warns that the title character is \u201cmaking the (*) beast with two backs.\u201d That character in this play takes a vow of silence after he is accused of having \"ensnared [the] soul and body\" of the title character, who repeats the words \"The handkerchief!\" to his wife before accusing Cassio of having an affair with her. Earlier, the antagonist warns the title character to beware the \"green-eyed monster.\" For 10 points, what Shakespeare play features Iago's plots of revenge against the title Moor?", "answer": "Othello [or The Tragedy of Othello, the Moor of Venice]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Othello</u></b> [or <b><u>The Tragedy of Othello, the Moor of Venice</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Othello", "The Tragedy of Othello, the Moor of Venice"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An associate in one of this author\u2019s novels has the code name R. \u201cCircle dancing\u201d is described in that novel, in which a professor nicknamed Voltaire invites a student to an evening gathering. A character questions whether God has intestines in another of this author\u2019s novels, which provides a Dictionary of Misunderstood Words. Another novel by him contains sections titled \u201cLitost\u201d and \u201cThe Angels.\u201d The epitaph (*) \u201cHe Wanted the Kingdom of God on Earth\" appears in a novel by this author in which the dog Karenin dies from a leg tumor and a character who quotes Beethoven\u2019s \u201cEs muss sein\u201d compares communists to Oedipus. Franz abandons Marie-Claude for Sabina, an enemy of kitsch, in that novel about Tomas and Tereza. For 10 points, name this Czech author of The Book of Laughter and Forgetting and The Unbearable Lightness of Being.", "answer": "Milan Kundera", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Milan Kundera</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Milan Kundera"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of this author\u2019s poems portrays the title creature as a \u201ccrouched Japanese warrior\u201d after describing a \u201cslow-burning stove.\u201d That poem later describes that creature as a \u201cblade of wheat\u201d and \u201cblack and brilliant.\u201d Another poem by this author describes the title objects \u201ccrossing and vanishing through their empty masks.\u201d The speaker mentions \u201comens which even now fly out of my hand\u201d in one poem by this author, which earlier described the \u201ccalm course of a star\u201d and the \u201cturning course of a river that goes curving, arriving (*) forever.\u201d This author of \u201cWind, Water, Stone\u201d wrote a poem whose first six and last six lines are the same and is 584 lines long. That poem, which is based on the Aztec calendar, begins \u201cwillow of crystal, a poplar of water.\u201d For 10 points, name this Mexican author of the poems \u201cSalamander\u201d and \u201cSunstone.\u201d", "answer": "Octavio Paz Lozano", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Octavio Paz <b><u>Lozano</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Octavio Paz Lozano"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At a party for this character, he refuses to leave his room, angering a man who is in charge of teaching songs to the community. This character\u2019s arrival saves another character from being sent to Iceland and causes a group of people to laugh at the word \u201cfather.\u201d This character\u2019s mother is seen as \u201cpromiscuous\u201d by members of her village, including by her lover Pop\u00e9. This character is the center of an interactive movie in which he whips himself repeatedly, and he reads passages from (*) Romeo and Juliet to Helmholtz. This character secludes himself to a lighthouse and hangs himself the day after an orgy. This man tries to start a rebellion after leaving his New Mexico reservation with Bernard Marx. For 10 points, name this character, the \u201csavage\u201d who becomes popular in the World State in Aldous Huxley\u2019s Brave New World.", "answer": "John the Savage", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>John the Savage</u></b>", "acceptable": ["John the Savage"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The speaker of this poem claims that \u201cAll [he] has is a voice / to undo the folded lie.\u201d This poem\u2019s speaker states that \u201cmismanagement and grief\u201d must be suffered \u201call again,\u201d and that \u201cAccurate scholarship\u201d will be able to \u201cFind what occurred at Linz.\u201d \u201cBlind skyscrapers\u201d are described in this poem, whose speaker claims to be composed of \u201cEros and dust.\u201d This poem claims that \u201cexiled Thucydides knew\u201d about a certain concept. Its speaker asserts \u201cThose to whom (*) evil is done do evil in return\u201d and hopes to shows \u201can affirming flame\u201d after mentioning \u201cwhat mad Nijinsky wrote about Diaghilev.\u201d This poem\u2019s author altered a famous line in a version reading \u201cWe must love one another and die.\u201d It begins on \u201cFifty-second Street,\u201d where its speaker \u201csits in\u201d a \u201cdive.\u201d For 10 points, name this W. H. Auden poem about the first day of World War II.", "answer": "\u201cSeptember 1, 1939\u201d", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cSeptember 1, 1939\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cSeptember 1, 1939\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this novel starts talking to the protagonist after leaving a biochemistry book on his carriage. The protagonist of this novel notes that a customer\u2019s wife was one of two people to care about him after she says, \u201cyou\u2019ve had an awful mean time,\u201d leading him to walk back to his farm in guilt. Andrew Hale is unable to give fifty dollars to the protagonist of this novel, who becomes jealous after seeing a woman in a red scarf dance with (*) Dennis Eady in a church. A character in this novel gets upset when she learns her favorite pickle dish was broken by a cat and glued together by the protagonist. The protagonist of this novel tries to sled into an elm tree at the bottom of a hill after Zeena fires his lover, her cousin. For 10 points, name Edith Wharton novel about the title character\u2019s love for Mattie Silver.", "answer": "Ethan Frome", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ethan Frome</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ethan Frome"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character suggests that she and another character should \"let ourselves go a little\" due to a raise after the New Year. This character fantasizes about an imaginary will that pays her everything \"at once in cash.\" This character pays a shilling for a Christmas tree before the appearance of her husband, who later tells her she can make as much noise as she wants practicing the tambourine for her upcoming (*) Tarantella dance. When this character, who is often called a \u201clittle lark,\u201d leaves the stage for the final time, the sound of a door shutting is heard from below. This character abandons the possibility of \"the most wonderful thing of all\" when her husband finds that she forged her father\u2019s signature to secure a loan from Krogstad. For 10 points, what character leaves her husband Torvald at the end of A Doll\u2019s House by Henrik Ibsen?", "answer": "Nora Helmer [prompt on Helmer]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nora Helmer</u></b> [prompt on <u>Helmer</u>]", "acceptable": ["Nora Helmer"], "promptable": ["Helmer"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}